// Questions - Debut

const debutQuestions = [
    {
    "question": "And I was right there beside him all summer long",
    "answers": ["Picture to Burn", "Tim McGraw", "Cold As You", "Should Have Said No"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "So watch me strike a match on all my wasted time",
    "answers": ["Picture to Burn", "Stay Beautiful", "Mary's Song (Oh My My My)", "Our Song"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "The only thing that keeps me wishing on a wishing star",
    "answers": ["A Perfectly Good Heart", "Our Song", "Teardrops on My Guitar", "Should Have Said No"],
    "correct": 2
    },

        {
    "question": "I'm just walking, trying to see through the rain coming down",
    "answers": ["Place in this World", "Stay Beautiful", "Cold As You", "Picture to Burn"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "Every smile you fake is so condescending, counting all the scars you made",
    "answers": ["Tim McGraw", "Invisible", "A Perfectly Good Heart", "Cold As You"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "I know I didn't read between the lines",
    "answers": ["Stay Beautiful", "The Outside", "Mary's Song (Oh My My My)", "Tim McGraw"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "But you don't tell anyone that you might not be the golden one",
    "answers": ["Our Song", "A Perfectly Good Heart", "Tied Together with a Smile", "Picture to Burn"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "It's hard to make a conversation, when he's taking my breath away",
    "answers": ["Stay Beautiful", "Our Song", "The Outside", "Mary's Song (Oh My My My)"],
    "correct": 0
    },
    
    {
    "question": "You say that the past is the past",
    "answers": ["A Perfectly Good Heart", "Tim McGraw", "Tied Together with a Smile", "Should Have Said No"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "Take me back to the house in the backyard tree",
    "answers": ["Should Have Said No", "Mary's Song (Oh My My My)", "The Outside", "Tim McGraw"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "I've heard every album, listened to the radio",
    "answers": ["Our Song", "Picture to Burn", "Teardrops on My Guitar", "A Perfectly Good Heart"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "And I don't try to hide my tears, my secrets or my deepest fears",
    "answers": ["Tim McGraw", "I'm Only Me When I'm With You", "The Outside", "Cold As You"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "There's a fire inside of you that can't help but shine through",
    "answers": ["Picture to Burn", "Tied Together with a Smile", "Invisible", "Should Have Said No"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "Why would you wanna make the very first scar",
    "answers": ["Our Song", "Tim McGraw", "Stay Beautiful", "A Perfectly Good Heart"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "I hate that stupid old pickup truck you never let me drive",
    "answers": ["Picture to Burn", "Should Have Said No", "Mary's Song (Oh My My My)", "Invisible"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "The water's high, you're jumping into it",
    "answers": ["Tim McGraw", "Tied Together with a Smile", "Cold As You", "Teardrops on My Guitar"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "She said, I was seven and you were nine",
    "answers": ["Picture to Burn", "I'm Only Me When I'm With You", "Cold As You", "Mary's Song (Oh My My My)"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "We could be a beautiful miracle, unbelievable",
    "answers": ["Our Song", "Should Have Said No", "Invisible", "Teardrops on My Guitar"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "Maybe I should've seen the signs, should've read the writing on the wall",
    "answers": ["A Perfectly Good Heart", "Our Song", "The Outside", "Cold As You"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "He said the way my blue eyes shined Put those Georgia stars to shame that night",
    "answers": ["Invisible", "Tim McGraw", "Tied Together with a Smile", "Picture to Burn"],
    "correct": 1
    },


];

// Questions Fearless

const fearlessQuestions = [
    {
    "question": "You take my hand and drag me head first",
    "answers": ["Fifteen", "Breathe", "Fearless", "Love Story"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "And you're dancing 'round your room when the night ends",
    "answers": ["The Way I Loved You", "The Best Day", "Change", "Fifteen"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "You'll be the prince and I'll be the princess",
    "answers": ["Love Story", "White Horse", "Breathe", "Untouchable"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "I could give you 50 reasons why I should be the one you choose",
    "answers": ["Change", "Hey Stephen", "Jump Then Fall", "You're Not Sorry"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "This ain't Hollywood, this is a small town",
    "answers": ["White Horse", "The Way I Loved You", "Love Story", "Fifteen"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "And you've got a smile that can light up this whole town",
    "answers": ["Breathe", "You Belong With Me", "White Horse", "Change"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "Every little bump in the road I tried to swerve",
    "answers": ["The Way I Loved You", "Hey Stephen", "Breathe", "The Best Day"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "Why do you have to put down my dreams so you're the only thing on my mind?",
    "answers": ["Change", "Tell Me Why", "The Other Side of the Door", "Come in with the Rain"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "You used to shine so bright but I watched all of it fade ",
    "answers": ["You're Not Sorry", "Tell Me Why", "The Other Side of the Door", "Come in with the Rain"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "You're so in love that you act insane",
    "answers": ["Fearless", "White Horse", "Change", "The Way I Loved You"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "Here's to silence, that cuts me to the core",
    "answers": ["Love Story", "Breathe", "Forever & Always", "Jump then Fall"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "It's the age of princesses and pirate ships",
    "answers": ["The Best Day", "Untouchable", "Superstar", "The Other Side of the Door"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "These walls that they put up to hold us back will fall down",
    "answers": ["Jump then Fall", "Come in with the Rain", "Change", "Today was a Fairytale"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "The bottom's gonna drop out from under our feet",
    "answers": ["Today was a Fairytale", "Jump then Fall", "Superstar", "Love Story"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "And now that you're close I feel like coming undone",
    "answers": ["Untouchable", "Breathe", "Fifteen", "White Horse"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "I could stand up and sing you a song but I don't wanna have to go that far",
    "answers": ["The Best Day", "Come in with the Rain", "Forever & Always", "You're Not Sorry"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "So dim that spotlight, tell me things like `I can't take my eyes off of you`",
    "answers": ["Jump Then Fall", "Untouchable", "You Belong With Me", "Superstar"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "After everything and that little black dress",
    "answers": ["The Other Side of the Door", "Forever & Always", "Fifteen", "Hey Stephen"],
    "correct": 0
    },
];

// Questions Speak Now

const speakNowQuestions = [

    {
    "question": "You learn my secrets and you figure out why I'm guarded",
    "answers": ["Never Grow Up", "Mine", "Love Story", "Enchanted"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "Get me with those green eyes, baby",
    "answers": ["Better than Revenge", "Haunted", "Mean", "Sparks Fly"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "You gave me all your love and all I gave you was goodbye",
    "answers": ["Back to December", "The Story of Us", "Mine", "Speak Now"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "Horrified looks from everyone in the room, but I'm only looking at you",
    "answers": ["Innocent", "Speak Now", "Mean", "Long Live"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "And you'll add my name to your long list of traitors",
    "answers": ["Ours", "Superman", "Dear John", "Better than Revenge"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "I bet you got pushed around, somebody made you cold",
    "answers": ["Mean", "Innocent", "Enchanted", "Speak Now"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "But you held your pride like you should have held me",
    "answers": ["Long Live", "Ours", "The Story of Us", "Love Story"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "Remember the footsteps, remember the words said",
    "answers": ["Better than Revenge", "Never Grow Up", "Sparks Fly", "Mean"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "The lingering question kept me up 2 AM, who do you love?",
    "answers": ["Enchanted", "Innocent", "Love Story", "Haunted"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "I think her ever present frown is a little troubling",
    "answers": ["Ours", "Mean", "Better than Revenge", "Dear John"],
    "correct": 2
    },

    {
    "question": "Your string of lights is still bright to me",
    "answers": ["The Story of Us", "Sparks Fly", "Love Story", "Innocent"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "Stood there and watched you walk away from everything we had",
    "answers": ["Long Live", "Haunted", "Dear John", "Enchanted"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "And I hope the sun shines and it's a beautiful day and something reminds you you wish you had stayed",
    "answers": ["Ours", "If This was a Movie", "Sparks Fly", "Last Kiss"],
    "correct": 3
    },

    {
    "question": "You traded your baseball cap for a crown",
    "answers": ["Superman", "Long Live", "The Story of Us", "Mean"],
    "correct": 1
    },

    {
    "question": "The stakes are high, the water's rough",
    "answers": ["Ours", "Love Story", "Innocent", "Back to December"],
    "correct": 0
    },

    {
    "question": "Now I'm pacing down the hall, chasing down your street",
    "answers": ["Speak Now", "Never Grow Up", "Haunted", "If This was a Movie"],
    "correct": 3
    },

     {
    "question": "But I hope someday you'll take me away, and save the day",
    "answers": ["Enchanted", "Ours", "Superman", "Better than Revenge"],
    "correct": 2
    },
];

const allErasQuestions = {
    debut: debutQuestions,
    fearless: fearlessQuestions,
    speakNow: speakNowQuestions
};

// General Code for the DOM
const pickEra = document.getElementById ("pick-era");
const quizSpace = document.getElementById ("quiz-space");
const questionEl = document.getElementById ("question");
const answers = document.getElementById ("answer-space");
const scoreEl = document.getElementById ("score");

let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
let currentQuestions = [];

/**
 * Show/hide sections as required
 */

function showSection(id) {
    document.getElementById(id).classList.remove("disappear");
}

function hideSection (id) {
    document.getElementById(id).classList.add("disappear");
}

// On DOM ready, show welcome and hide others
window.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
  showSection("website-opener");
  hideSection("opening-instructions");
  hideSection("logo");
  hideSection("pick-era");
});

/**
 * On clicking "lets go", take the user to the instructions page
 */

function startButton() {
    console.log("start button clicked");
    showSection("logo");
    showSection("opening-instructions");
    hideSection("website-opener");
}

/**
 * on clicking "it's been a long time coming" the user is taken to the era 
 * selection option
 */

function pickButton() {
    console.log ("It's been a long time coming clicked");
    hideSection("opening-instructions");
    showSection("pick-era");
}

/**
 * select Era then open quiz
 */

const eraButtons = document.getElementsByClassName ("era-selector-button");

for (let button of eraButtons) {
    button.addEventListener("click", function() {
        let gameChoice = this.getAttribute ("data-type");
        console.log("Clicked era", gameChoice);

        if (allErasQuestions[gameChoice]) {
            console.log ("Loading questions for", gameChoice);
            hideSection ("pick-era");
            showSection ("quiz-space");
            showSection ("additional-buttons");
            revealEra(gameChoice);
            startQuiz (allErasQuestions [gameChoice]);
        } else {
            console.log ("No game questions found for", gameChoice)
        }
    });
}

/**
 *  Format Era titles for readability at top of page
 */

function formatEraName(era) {
  const eraNames = {
    debut: "Debut",
    fearless: "Fearless",
    speakNow: "Speak Now",
    red: "Red",
    nineteeneightynine: "1989",
    reputation: "Reputation",
    lover: "Lover",
    folkloreAndEvermore: "Folklore & Evermore",
    midnights: "Midnights",
    ttpd: "The Tortured Poets Department",
  };
  return eraNames [era];
}
  
  function revealEra (era) {
    eraEl.innerText = formatEraName(era);
    }

// Show correct Era at top of quiz
const eraEl = document.getElementById("show");

/**
 * shuffle questions
 */

function shuffleArray(array) {
    return [...array].sort(() => Math.random() - 0.5);
}

// Quiz Logic - load and shuffle questions to only show 15)
function startQuiz (questionsArray){
    currentQuestions = shuffleArray(questionsArray).slice(0, 15);
    currentQuestionIndex = 0;
    showQuestion (currentQuestions[currentQuestionIndex]);
    score = 0;
    scoreEl.innerText = `0 / 15`
}

const answerButtons = [
    document.querySelector(".answer1"),
    document.querySelector(".answer2"),
    document.querySelector(".answer3"),
    document.querySelector(".answer4")
]

/**
 * Show questions
 */

function showQuestion (quest) {
    questionEl.innerText = quest.question;

    // Enable button on each individual question
    quest.answers.forEach((answer, index) => {
        const btn = answerButtons [index];
        btn.disabled = false;
        btn.classList.remove("correct-answer", "wrong-answer");
        btn.innerText = answer;

        btn.onclick = () => {
            showAnswer (btn, index === quest.correct);
        };
    });
}

/**
 * Show answers
 */

function showAnswer (button, isCorrect) {
    // Update score if correct
    if (isCorrect) {
        score++;
        scoreEl.innerText = `${score} / 15`;
    }

    // Disable buttons so player cannot choose another and show colour highlight
    answerButtons.forEach((btn, index) => {
        btn.disabled = true;

      // Change colour to indicate if correct or incorrect answer
    if (index === currentQuestions [currentQuestionIndex].correct) {
        btn.classList.add("correct-answer");
    }    

    if (btn === button && !isCorrect) {
        btn.classList.add("wrong-answer");
    }
});

    // Jump to next question automatically after 1.5 seconds
    currentQuestionIndex++;
    if (currentQuestionIndex < currentQuestions.length) {
        setTimeout(() => {
            showQuestion(currentQuestions[currentQuestionIndex]);
        }, 1500);
    } else {
        setTimeout (() => {
            endQuiz ();
        }, 1500);
    }
}

// Score tracker
let score = 0

/** 
 * End Quiz
 */

function endQuiz () {
    hideSection("quiz-space");
    hideSection ("additional-buttons");
    showSection ("final-score-space");
    finalScore();
}

/**
 * Final score messages
 */

function finalScore () {
    const finalScoreEl = document.getElementById("final-score");

    if (score === 15) {
        finalScoreEl.innerHTML = `
        <strong>Your final score is ${score} / 15!</strong>

        <p>Okay, wait a minute... you got a perfect score?! Are you kidding us right now?!</p>
        
        <p>This wasn't just knowing the answers <em>"All Too Well"</em>; it was <em>"(Mr) Perfectly Fine"</em> taken to an entirely new level! You didn't just pass; you absolutely conquered that quiz like it was <em>"The Great War"</em>, and you were the only one left standing.</p>
        
        <p>You're not just a Swiftie; you're a certified <em>"Mastermind!"</em> It's as if you know the lyrics better than Taylor Swift herself sometimes. This is your moment to really make the whole place shimmer!</p>
        
        So, to the quiz champion, CONGRATULATIONS! You've officially proven you're the ultimate, undisputed, 100%-scoring quiz legend. Go celebrate like you just won a Grammy; you absolutely earned it.`
        
        `<button onclick="homeButton()";>Home</button>`
    }
    else if (score >= 12 && score <= 14) {
        finalScoreEl.innerHTML = `
        <strong>Your final score is ${score} / 15!</strong>

        <p>Did you have <em>"The Lucky One"</em> on repeat while studying, or are you just a <em>"Mastermind</em> when it comes to all things Taylor? Because you absolutely slayed that quiz like it was a surprise album drop!</p>
        
        <p>We bet you were feeling <em>"Fearless"</em> walking into that, and now you're probably singing <em>"Long Live"</em> at the top of your lungs. You didn't just know the answers, you knew them <em>"All Too Well."</em></p>
        
        <p>Consider this your <em>"Picture to Burn"</em> moment for anyone who doubted your Swiftie knowledge.</p> 
        
        <p>You've officially entered your champion Era, and honestly, it looks <em>"Gorgeous"</em> on you!</p>
        
        Congratulations, you magnificent, lyrical genius! Now, if you'll excuse us, we're just wondering if you'll ever let us in on your <em>"Mastermind"</em> strategy, because we're not as cool as you.`;
    }

       else if (score >= 9 && score <= 11) {
        finalScoreEl.innerHTML = `
        <strong>Your final score is ${score} / 15!</strong>

        <p>Okay, so someone just jumped into that Taylor Swift quiz, and you know what? That's what truly matters! You showed up, gave it your all, and you're still a brilliant Swiftie.</p>
        
        <p>Sometimes, you don't know all the little secret Easter eggs, and honestly, that's totally okay! The whole point is to have fun. You just gotta <em>"Shake It Off"</em> when it comes to the score and remember what a dedicated fan you are.</p>
        
        Don't even sweat it! There's always a <em>"Begin Again"</em> moment for the next quiz, and we know you'll absolutely crush it. Congratulations on playing along!`;
    }

     else if (score >= 4 && score <= 9) {
        finalScoreEl.innerHTML = `
        <strong>Your final score is ${score} / 15!</strong>
        
        <p>Well, that quiz was certainly a <em>"Bad Blood"</em> moment for some of us, wasn't it? But honestly, who cares if you didn't ace every single question, the important thing is you showed up, you played, and you still have an <em>"Invisible String"</em> connecting you to all things Taylor!</p>
      
        <p>Maybe you just had a <em>"Glitch"</em> on a few answers, or perhaps you were too busy jamming to the music in your head to focus on the trivia. Either way, there's absolutely no need to </em>"Shake It Off"</em>.</p>
    
        Consider this just a little <em>"Long Story Short"</em> moment. It's all about the fun, plus, now you have even more reason to dive back into the discography. You can always <em>"Begin Again"</em> with another quiz!`;
    }

     else if (score >= 1 && score <= 4) {
        finalScoreEl.innerHTML = `
        <strong>Your final score is ${score} / 15!</strong>
        
        <p>Okay, so maybe that quiz was more of a <em>"Death By A Thousand Cuts"</em> than a <em>"Love Story"</em> for you, but hold up! You got a few right, and in the grand scheme of things, that's like finding a secret message in one of Taylor's album booklets - a small victory, but a victory nonetheless!</p>
        
        <p>No need to <em>"Shake It Off"</em> in despair, because seriously, the fact that you even showed up and faced the music makes you a <em>"Fearless"</em> fan in our book. Maybe you were just too busy feeling <em>"22"</em> and having a blast to remember every deep cut, and that's perfectly okay!</p>
        
        Consider this just a <em>"Long Story Short"</em> moment on your Swiftie journey. It's not about being a <em>"Mastermind"</em> every time, it's about the shared love for the music. Plus, now you've got a whole new set of lyrics to dive into for next time. You can always <em>"Begin Again"</em> with another quiz!`;
    }

        else if (score === 0) {
        finalScoreEl.innerHTML = `
        <strong>Your final score is ${score} / 15!</strong>
        
        <p>Okay, so you just took a Taylor Swift quiz and landed squarely in a <em>"Blank Space"</em> when it came to the answers, huh? You know what? That's not a loss; that's just a clean slate ready to be filled with all the amazing Taylor knowledge you're about to gain!</p>
        
        <p>There's absolutely no need to <em>"Shake It Off"</em> in despair because, honestly, showing up and giving it a shot is a <em>"Fearless"</em> move in itself. Maybe you were just too busy feeling <em>"22"</em> and having a good time, or perhaps you were already mentally planning your next eras fit!</p>
        
        <p>Consider this just a <em>"Long Story Short"</em> moment. The real win isn't about the score; it's about the pure, unadulterated love for Taylor's music that brought you to the quiz in the first place.</p> 

        You're still connected by an <em>"Invisible String"</em> to this fandom. Plus, now you have all the songs to re-listen to and all the lyrics to learn! We're confident that next time, you'll be singing a different tune and going <em>"Clean"</em> on that scoreboard!`;
    }
}

/**
 * Add function to make home button work
 */

function homeButton() {
    console.log ("home button clicked");
    hideSection("quiz-space");
    hideSection("final-score-space");
    hideSection("pick-era");
    hideSection("opening-instructions");
    hideSection("additional-buttons");
    hideSection("logo");
    showSection("website-opener");
}

/**
 * Add function to make the help button work
 */

function helpButton () {
    console.log ("help button clicked");
    hideSection("quiz-space");
    hideSection("final-score-space");
    hideSection("pick-era");
    hideSection ("additional-buttons")
    showSection ("opening-instructions");
}

/**
 * Add function to make another era button work
 */

function anotherEraButton () {
    console.log ("another era clicked");
    hideSection ("quiz-space");
    hideSection("final-score-space");
    hideSection ("additional-buttons");
    
    // Reset quiz for new questions

    score = 0;
    currentQuestionIndex = 0;
    currentQuestions = [];

    // Show pick era interface

    showSection ("pick-era");


}